A Guide to the Benjamin Penhollow Shillaber Collection
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #7493-a
Benjamin Penhollow Shillaber Collection 1857-1890
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
7493-a
21 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Deposit [ 1963 Dec 17 ] 1965 Oct 15
Item Listing
- Manuscripts
  - Page concerning "Mrs. Partington", 1859 Apr 6; AMsS, 1 p.
  - Poem, beginning "Of all the projects.. .", 1874 Sep 17; AMsS, 1 p.
  - Poem, " A Golden Epithalamium ", [1875]; AMsS, 3 p.
    [Dedicated to Governor and Mrs. Elston Stone on their golden anniversary.]
  - Poem, " A Few Feeble Lines ", 1881 Mar 10; AMsS, 3 p.
    [Dedicated to the Siloan Lodge on its anniversary.]
  - Quotation from " Ruth Partington ", [1890] Apr 5; AMsS, 1 p.
    [Signed by Benjamin Penhallow Shillaber. ]
  - Autobiographical sketch, n. d.; AMs, 2 p.
- Letters
  - Benjamin Penhallow Shillaber to L. W. Burnham, 1857 Dec 19; ALS, 1 p.
    [Hopes to meet him on Tuesday or Wednesday when he will be in Chicago. ]
  - Benjamin Penhallow Shillaber to Mrs. Ashby, 1864 Feb 17; ALS, 1 p.
    [Believes his contribution went to a good cause.]
  - Benjamin Penhallow Shillaber to [Charles Follen] Adams, 1874 Mar 24; ALS, 1 p.
    [Introduces William E. Ford to Adams; says that Ford wishes to engage Adams for a lecture; promises him a quality audience with reporters present.]
  - Benjamin Penhallow Shillaber to F. S. Wood, 1874 Dec 25; ALS, 1 p.
    [Apologizes for delayed reply to letter.]
  - Benjamin Penhallow Shillaber to William Winter, 1877 Oct 30; ALS, 1 p.
    [Asks him to introduce Shillaber's relatives, Mr. and Mrs. Theodore Shillaber, to celebrities such as [Joseph] Jefferson, William Cullen Bryant, etc.]
  - Benjamin Penhallow Shillaber to "My Dear young Friend", 1882 Jan 13; ALS, 1 p.
    [Compliments and encourages young autograph seeker on his pursuits; hopes he will make a name for himself so one day he too will be approached by autograph seekers.]
  - Benjamin Penhallow Shillaber to "My dear old friend", 1884 Jul 31; ALS, 4 p.
    [Says he is moved by the correspondent's letter and poem on the occasion of his 70th birthday; comforts him on the recent bad crop; says he is irritated by the common view that disasters are sent by God to test people's patience and endurance; comments on his birthday and the attention he received; believes James G. Blaine's political fortunes locally are not good because of changing political affiliations of the electorate.]
  - Benjamin Penhallow Shillaber to W. P. Young, 1889 Jan 28; ALS, 1 p.
    [Gives the names of publishers of out of print Partington books; inquires about the effect of a liniment.]
  - Benjamin Penhallow Shillaber to Mrs. Morris P. Ferris, 1889 Apr 3; ALS, 2 p.
    [Tells life story even though he is unsure what motivates him; says he has turned down all similar requests; discusses his relationship with the press and his contribution to newspapers; says he is presently a weekly correspondent of the
    Hartford Evening Post
    . ]
  - Benjamin Penhallow Shillaber to "My dear friend", 1889 Jun 25; ALS, 2 p.
    [Apologizes for his late note of thanks for a satirical piece on the inauguration anniversary; comments on its style; discusses his poor health and his present circumstances; encloses his "production" for this year's celebration of Bunker Hill Day.]
  - Benjamin Penhallow Shillaber to Mrs. Morris P. Ferris, 1889 Jul 11; ALS, 4 p.
    [Praises a poem she sent him; discusses his writing ability; tells her about his family, his health, and his plans for the immediate future.]
  - Benjamin Penhallow Shillaber to "My dear friend", 1890 Jun 12; ALS, 1 p.
    [Gives his regards; says he has returned from a trip with his son; comments on the heat.]
  - Benjamin Penhallow Shillaber to "My Dear Sir", Jul 13; ALS, 1 p.
    [Asks him to listen to the interesting idea of Mr. Page.]
  - Benjamin Penhallow Shillaber to Bro[ther] Orr, n. d.; ALS, 1 p.
    [Regard his literary contributions to the [magazine]; wants the proofs sent to him.]
- Photograph
  - Benjamin Penhallow Shillaber, profile, signed, n. d.; Photograph